# Elia Bellussi, MBA

Orbassano, Torino ITALY | +39-333-689-2117 | +44-7775-701751

e.bellussi@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/eliabellussi/ | https://github.com/ebellussi

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate about technology with 10+ years of experience: working in relationship management, system engineering, and project management with stakeholders and clients such as Italian Public Sector, GE Avio Aero (aerospace), Eutelsat - Skylogic (telecommunication), Banca Intesa Sanpaolo (finance) for the complex environment and specialized in technological innovation, digital transformation, emerging technologies, pre-sale strategy, and open innovation.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**ALMAVIVA** — Turin, Italy

June 2020 – Present

# **Innovation Strategist**

- Responsible for ideation of customised solutions for public administrations and the national healthcare system, leading their digital transformation.
- Designing innovation processes, methodologies, and strategies, implementing networks of stakeholders.
- Coordinating teams in European calls for tenders, focusing on excellence and impact.

# **SAA – SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT —** Turin, Italy

Nov 2020 - Present

#### **Teacher Assistant**

• Overseeing case studies analysis for the course in Management Information Systems and Internal Control.

# **CONSOFT SISTEM!** — Turin, Italy

May 2011 – June 2020

# Senior System Engineer

- Responsible for projects on continual service development through process design and analytics with a particular focus on KPIs and quality management for GE Avio Aero and Skylogic, a subsidiary of Eutelsat.
- Managed a tailored monitoring system related to the effectiveness of the company's infrastructure of 7.000 servers for Intesa Sanpaolo, as a product owner in an agile team.
- Contributed to the development and management of different projects/B2B products, in collaboration between the enterprise service desk and the enterprise projects development team for GE Avio Aero.

# **Corporate Business Solutions Manager**

- Responsible for the Big Data practice of the company, creating a cross functional team and developing the business plan.
- Provided courses on noSQL with a particular focus on MongoDB for bTicino, a subsidiary of Legrand group.
- Trained and tutored a colleague for a project on Big Data Analytics with a Hadoop infrastructure.

# DIGITAL360 — Milan, Italy

Feb 2020 – Present

## **Contributing Writer**

• Writing articles on Design Thinking, Data Strategy, Scenario Planning published on Italian online magazines.

## **COMAU** — Rivalta di Turin, Italy

Feb 2017

#### **Guest Lecturer**

- Conducting lectures for an Executive Master of Digital Innovation, collaborating with ESCP Business School (Birmingham, UK).
- Training and motivating a group of 30 executive students on coding and its impact in digital transformation.

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **SOCIAL INNOVATION TEAM** — Turin, Italy

March 2021 – Present

#### Start-up Mentor

• Reorganised, redesigned, and strengthened the business strategy, the product development, and the financial statements.

#### Nov 2020 – Present

# Start-up Mentor

• Mentored and trained teams on design thinking, helping them to develop their business model and strategies.

# **STARTUP GEEKS** — Milan, Italy

Nov 2020 – Present

#### Start-up Mentor

• Supervised teams following the program, providing support and information to be able to complete the assignments.

# RINASCITA DIGITALE — Milan, Italy

May 2020 – Present

#### **Guest Speaker**

• Conducting live webinars on Design Thinking, Data Strategy, Scenario Planning shared through YouTube.

### **EUROPEAN COMMISSION** — Brussels, Belgium

Apr 2020 - June 2020

#### Start-up Mentor

• Helping 5 teams (one won), for EUvsVirus Hackathon, on technology, business analysis, and marketing plan.

### **VOICEMED** — Stockholm, Sweden

Apr 2020 – May 2020

# Full Stack Developer

• Developing, with React, the Italian version of the website and of the app to gather data from an interactive survey.

#### EDUCATION

# Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence (MSc)

Expected 2021

Università Degli Studi di Turin — Turin, Italy

Natural Language Processing – Computer Vision – Multi Agents System – Al Ethics

### Master of Science in Disruptive Innovation (MDI)

Mar 2020

HULT International Business School — San Francisco, USA – GPA: 3.61 with Distinction

Design thinking – Scenario Planning – Leading Digital Innovation – Co-Creation Network – Open Innovation

#### Master of Business Administration (MBA)

Aug 2019

HULT International Business School — London, UK – GPA: 3.26

Major in Project Management – Minor in Marketing & Sales – Campuses: London, Dubai, and Shanghai

#### Bachelor of Computer Science (BSc)

Oct 2011

Università Degli Studi di Turin — Turin, Italy

Artificial Intelligence

### LANGUAGES \_

Italian (Native); English (Advanced); Spanish (Basic).

#### SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Work Authorization: EU citizen.s

Languages: Italian (native), English (fluent), Spanish (elementary).

Certifications: ITIL V3 Foundation, Foundations in Design Thinking (IDEO), Professional Scrum Master I (Scrum.org).

Memberships: IEEE (https://www.ieee.org). Club Dirigenti Informatici (http://www.clubdi.org/).